JOSEPH AKINWOLE

Frontend Developer

Akure, Ondo State 340110 josey359h7mgj_zoq@indeedemail.com +234 703 685 7945

Hello, my name is Joseph, and I'm a full-stack developer. After pursuing a BA in linguistics for three years, I discovered my passion for coding and never looked back $\mathbb{Q} \$ I enjoy building UIs from the ground up and bringing them to life with clean, efficient code \mathbb{Z} .

My expertise lies in ReactJS, React Native, NodeJS, SQL, and various styling tools such as Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Sass, and CSS & I'm also familiar with Git and can manage code versions and branches with ease.

As a lifelong learner, I'm always expanding my skillset and currently exploring Flutter $\mbox{\ensuremath{\&}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\&}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\&}}$. I believe that technology can create a better future, and I'm excited to be a part of that vision $\mbox{\ensuremath{\&}}\mbox{\ensuremath{\&}}$.

Personal Details

Currently Employed: Yes Date of Birth: 1999-03-24

Highest Level of Education: Higher National Diploma

Industry: Information Technology

NYSC Status: Completed

Work Experience

Front-end developer

Core Outreach Services - Dallas, TX January 2023 to Present

I currently work as a full-time Frontend Developer at Core Outreach Services in Dallas, Texas. I have been in this position for five months since January 2023. As a remote worker, my main skills include developing web applications and front-end development.

Front End Developer

JDLAB - Niger

November 2021 to December 2022

Roles

- Upgraded JSP (JDLab School Portal) A School Management System
- Implemented all major & minor components of Student and Application Portal with redesigned UI.
- Handled major User interactions (For Students) and functionalities from payments to results and Admission Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, ReactJs, BootStrap, StyledComponents
- Handled JDLab Academy
- Tutored Students on Frontend Development Courses.

• Handled Classes in JDLab Summer Camp

Front End Developer

Google Developer Student Club(GDSC) Fuoye - Ekiti November 2019 to October 2021

Freelance Web Developer & Graphics Designer

Freelancer.com
December 2019 to May 2020

Education

Bachelor's Degree in computational linguistics

Federal University of Oye - Ekiti

January 2016 to 2021

Skills

- HTML (4 years)
- CSS (4 years)
- JavaScript (3 years)
- Reactjs (2 years)
- React native (2 years)
- Sass (1 year)
- TailwindCss (2 years)
- NodeJs (2 years)
- . Net (1 year)
- Redux (2 years)
- Python (1 year)
- jQuery (1 year)

Languages

- English Fluent
- French Expert
- Spanish Intermediate

Links

https://facebook.com/joseph.akinwole.7/

https://github.com/Joebim

https://joebim.github.io/Mon-Portfolio/

https://twitter.com/akinwole_joseph

https://www.instagram.com/josephakinwole/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-akinwole-71415a198/

Certifications and Licenses

Frontend Development Certification

September 2020 to November 2020

GSDC (Google Student Developer Group)

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1544kEGIHJnoJMVXAB AYiQ1HHkOVZ kG/view?usp=sharing (2020)

Certificate of Membership of Niger State ICT Community Development Service (CDS).

November 2021 to November 2022

ICT Community Development Service (NYSC)

Workplace Ethics and Attitude

Udemy — Workplace Ethics and Attitude

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qYkEY25xVklhS87nEFzwgTcYvZR8KXJu/view?usp=sharing (2022)

HTML & CSS Certification - Udemy

March 2023 to Present

Udemy course HTML & CSS Certification

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LugNeVEhHXMFtBYegIVBLPg8MEhkPtYn/view?usp=sharing

CSS and JavaScript Certification - udemy

March 2023 to Present

Udemy course CSS and JavaScript

https://drive.google.com/file/d/17nBr8doF8Ta0zGMI4IddjQsoPOPTqW4W/view?usp=sharing

Groups

Google Student Developer Group

January 2020 to Present

Github Student Developers

November 2022 to Present

ALX Software Engineer

February 2023 to Present